When people find out I write about time management,
当人们发现我写 关于时间管理的文章时，
they assume two things.
他们都会假设两件事：
One is that I'm always on time,
第一，我永远都准时，
and I'm not.
但我并不是。
I have four small children,
我有四个小孩，
and I would like to blame them for my occasional tardiness,
我偶尔将迟到归咎于他们，
but sometimes it's just not their fault.
不过有时候真的不是因为他们。
I was once late to my own speech on time management.
我有一次在去我的一个关于 时间管理的演讲时迟到了。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
We all had to just take a moment together and savor that irony.
我们都需要一点时间去好好地 体味一下这有多么讽刺。
The second thing they assume is that I have lots of tips and tricks
第二，人们总是假设我有很多关于
for saving bits of time here and there.
如何节省时间的贴士和技巧。
Sometimes I'll hear from magazines that are doing a story along these lines,
有时候我听说一些杂志 在写这方面的故事，
generally on how to help their readers find an extra hour in the day.
通常都是关于教读者如何 在一天中获得额外一个小时。
And the idea is that we'll shave bits of time off everyday activities,
基本思路就是从日常的 每个活动中挤出一点时间，
add it up,
加起来，
and we'll have time for the good stuff.
然后我们就有时间去做 更有意思的事情了。
I question the entire premise of this piece, but I'm always interested
我对这个说法持保留意见， 不过我还是愿意听听
in hearing what they've come up with before they call me.
他们在找我之前有什么想法。
Some of my favorites:
我最喜欢的几个是：
doing errands where you only have to make right-hand turns --
只完成那些只需要右转的事；
(Laughter)
（笑声）
Being extremely judicious in microwave usage:
在用微波炉时，要极度审慎：
it says three to three-and-a-half minutes on the package,
当食物包装上面写了3到3.5分钟时，
we're totally getting in on the bottom side of that.
我们要挑时间最短的那个。
And my personal favorite, which makes sense on some level,
我个人最喜欢的是， 录下你最喜欢看的电视剧，
is to DVR your favorite shows so you can fast-forward through the commercials.
然后你就可以跳过广告了。 其实在某个程度上，还是挺有道理的。
That way, you save eight minutes every half hour,
这样，你每半个小时就可以挤出八分钟。
so in the course of two hours of watching TV,
那么你葱用来看电视的两个小时中，
you find 32 minutes to exercise.
可以挤出32分钟锻炼的时间。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
Which is true.
倒的确是这么回事儿。
You know another way to find 32 minutes to exercise?
你还知道其他可以找到 32分钟锻炼时间的方法吗？
Don't watch two hours of TV a day, right?
不要每天都看两个小时 电视就行了，对吧？
(Laughter)
（笑声）
Anyway, the idea is we'll save bits of time here and there, add it up,
总之，就是要在各处都省点时间，
we will finally get to everything we want to do.
加起来就有时间 做我们想做的事了。
But after studying how successful people spend their time
但在我了解成功的人如何分配时间，
and looking at their schedules hour by hour,
并看过了他们的时间表后，
I think this idea has it completely backward.
我觉得这个想法是 完全本末倒置的。
We don't build the lives we want by saving time.
我们不是通过节省时间来 打造我们想过的生活。
We build the lives we want,
我们应该先建立我们想要的生活，
and then time saves itself.
时间就会自然而然节省出来。
Here's what I mean.
我来解释一下。
I recently did a time diary project
我最近有个时间日记项目，
looking at 1,001 days in the lives of extremely busy women.
观察最忙碌的女士生命中的1001天。
They had demanding jobs, sometimes their own businesses,
她们工作繁忙， 有时候是自己的生意，
kids to care for, maybe parents to care for,
有时候要照顾自己的孩子， 或者是照顾父母，
community commitments --
还有服务社区等等——
busy, busy people.
都是一些很忙的人。
I had them keep track of their time for a week
我让她们记录了一星期的行程，
so I could add up how much they worked and slept,
计算她们工作和睡觉的时间，
and I interviewed them about their strategies, for my book.
为了我的书，我还采访 了解了她们的常用策略。
One of the women whose time log I studied
其中一个被我研究过时间表的女士，
goes out on a Wednesday night for something.
在一个周三晚上出去了一趟，
She comes home to find that her water heater has broken,
回家发现她的热水器坏了，
and there is now water all over her basement.
地下室都被水淹了。
If you've ever had anything like this happen to you,
如果你也遇到过这种事儿的话，
you know it is a hugely damaging, frightening, sopping mess.
你会知道眼前的景象 多么令人崩溃和沮丧。
So she's dealing with the immediate aftermath that night,
于是那个晚上她立刻着手处理，
next day she's got plumbers coming in,
第二天她找了一个水管工，
day after that, professional cleaning crew dealing with the ruined carpet.
第三天找了专业的清理人员 来处理损坏的地毯。
All this is being recorded on her time log.
所有这些都算在了她的时间表内。
Winds up taking seven hours of her week.
总共花了她一周中的七个小时。
Seven hours.
七个小时。
That's like finding an extra hour in the day.
这就等于一周七天 每天都要挤出一个小时。
But I'm sure if you had asked her at the start of the week,
但是假如你在这一周 刚开始时就问她，
"Could you find seven hours to train for a triathlon?"
“你能在这周抽出七个小时 来参加铁人三项吗？”，
"Could you find seven hours to mentor seven worthy people?"
“你能在这周抽出七个小时 指导七个有潜力的人吗？“
I'm sure she would've said what most of us would've said,
我确定她会像大多数人一样，
which is, "No -- can't you see how busy I am?"
说，”怎么可能，你看不出我有多忙吗？“
Yet when she had to find seven hours
但是她最后不得不抽出七个小时，
because there is water all over her basement,
因为她的地下室都被水淹了，
she found seven hours.
她挤出了这七个小时。
And what this shows us is that time is highly elastic.
这件事告诉我们：时间是有弹性的。
We cannot make more time,
我们不能创造更多时间，
but time will stretch to accommodate what we choose to put into it.
但是时间会自己调整去适应 我们选择去做的事情。
And so the key to time management
所以时间管理的关键就是
is treating our priorities
对待最重要的事情应该像
as the equivalent of that broken water heater.
对待那个坏了的热水器一样。
To get at this,
要做到这一点，
I like to use language from one of the busiest people I ever interviewed.
我要借用我采访过最忙的人的话。
By busy, I mean she was running a small business
她经营着一个小企业，
with 12 people on the payroll,
请了十二名员工，
she had six children in her spare time.
空余时间她还要照顾六个孩子。
I was getting in touch with her to set up an interview
我联系上了她，想要采访她关于
on how she "had it all" -- that phrase.
她是怎么做到“无所不能”的。
I remember it was a Thursday morning,
我记得那是一个星期四的早晨，
and she was not available to speak with me.
她没时间和我说话。
Of course, right?
当然了，她很忙。
But the reason she was unavailable to speak with me
但是她没时间和我说话的原因是，
is that she was out for a hike,
她去远足了。
because it was a beautiful spring morning,
因为那是春季一个美丽的清晨，
and she wanted to go for a hike.
所以她去远足了。
So of course this makes me even more intrigued,
这样的她让我变得更感兴趣了，
and when I finally do catch up with her, she explains it like this.
当我最终联系上她时，
She says, "Listen Laura, everything I do,
她说：“听我说，劳拉， 我做的所有的事情，
every minute I spend, is my choice."
我花的每分每秒，都是我的选择。”
And rather than say,
所以与其说，
"I don't have time to do x, y or z,"
”我没有时间做这个，这个，或者那个。”
she'd say, "I don't do x, y or z because it's not a priority."
她会说：”我不做这些事情因为 这些不是我的首要任务。“
"I don't have time," often means "It's not a priority."
“我没有时间”的意思通常是 ”那不是我的首要任务”。
If you think about it, that's really more accurate language.
其实你想想， 那的确是更准确的说法。
I could tell you I don't have time to dust my blinds,
我可能会告诉你我没有 时间清理百叶窗，
but that's not true.
但那不是真的。
If you offered to pay me $100,000 to dust my blinds,
假如你愿意付我10万美金 让我给百叶窗除尘，
I would get to it pretty quickly.
我会马上就去做。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
Since that is not going to happen,
既然那不可能发生，
I can acknowledge this is not a matter of lacking time;
我可以说不是因为时间不够，
it's that I don't want to do it.
而是我不想做。
Using this language reminds us that time is a choice.
这么说提醒了我们， 时间是一种选择。
And granted,
我会告诉你，
there may be horrible consequences for making different choices,
当然，不同的选择有时候会
I will give you that.
带来可怕的后果。
But we are smart people,
但是我们都是聪明人，
and certainly over the long run,
从长远来看，
we have the power to fill our lives
我们有能力去选择一些值得做的事，
with the things that deserve to be there.
来填补我们生命中的时间。
So how do we do that?
那么我们应该怎么做呢？
How do we treat our priorities
我们要如何像对待那个
as the equivalent of that broken water heater?
坏了的热水器一样 对待我们的首要任务？
Well, first we need to figure out what they are.
首先，我们需要找出哪些事最重要。
I want to give you two strategies for thinking about this.
我想给你们分享两个技巧。
The first, on the professional side:
第一个，从职业的角度来说：
I'm sure many people coming up to the end of the year
我相信许多人在年底的时候
are giving or getting annual performance reviews.
会发出或者收到年度绩效审查。
You look back over your successes over the year,
你回头看看这一年的成功和
your "opportunities for growth."
“成长的机会”。
And this serves its purpose,
这的确起到了它的作用，
but I find it's more effective to do this looking forward.
但是我发现往前看会更有效。
So I want you to pretend it's the end of next year.
我想让你们把这当做下一年的年底。
You're giving yourself a performance review,
你在给自己做年度绩效审查，
and it has been an absolutely amazing year for you professionally.
在专业方面，这一年的表现非常出众。
What three to five things did you do that made it so amazing?
是哪三到五件事使 这一年变得如此出众？
So you can write next year's performance review now.
你现在就可以写明年的绩效审查。
And you can do this for your personal life, too.
你也可以在个人生活方面这么做。
I'm sure many of you, like me, come December,
我相信你们许多人，包括我，在十二月，
get cards that contain these folded up sheets of colored paper,
都会收到这种夹着彩色纸的卡片。
on which is written what is known as the family holiday letter.
上面写着“家庭假日信件”。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
Bit of a wretched genre of literature, really,
听起来像是一个挺悲惨的文学题材，
going on about how amazing everyone in the household is,
谈论家里每个人有多了不起，
or even more scintillating,
或者更精彩点，
how busy everyone in the household is.
家里每个人有多忙。
But these letters serve a purpose,
但是这些信有它们的用处，
which is that they tell your friends and family
它们告诉你的朋友和家人
what you did in your personal life that mattered to you over the year.
你这一年里做了什么对 个人生活有意义的事。
So this year's kind of done,
那么今年快要结束了，
but I want you to pretend it's the end of next year,
我想让你假装这是明年的年底，
and it has been an absolutely amazing year
对你和你在乎的人来说，
for you and the people you care about.
这都是无与伦比的一年。
What three to five things did you do that made it so amazing?
哪三到五件事让你这一年 表现如此出色？
So you can write next year's family holiday letter now.
其实你现在就可以写 明年的家庭假日信件了。
Don't send it.
先不要发出去。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
Please, don't send it.
真的，不要发出去。
But you can write it.
但是你可以写。
And now, between the performance review and the family holiday letter,
现在，有了绩效评估和写给家人的信，
we have a list of six to ten goals we can work on in the next year.
我们就有了六到十个 明年可以努力的目标。
And now we need to break these down into doable steps.
我们需要先把他们分成 可行的阶段性任务。
So maybe you want to write a family history.
或许你要写一个家族传记。
First, you can read some other family histories,
首先，你可以读读别人的家族历史，
get a sense for the style.
了解一下大概的风格。
Then maybe think about the questions you want to ask your relatives,
然后可以想象你要问亲戚的问题，
set up appointments to interview them.
约定和他们见面谈话的时间。
Or maybe you want to run a 5K.
或者你想要参加一个 五千米的短程马拉松。
So you need to find a race and sign up, figure out a training plan,
你需要先找一个竞赛报名， 再做一个培训计划，
and dig those shoes out of the back of the closet.
从衣柜底下翻出你的运动鞋。
And then -- this is key --
然后——这是关键——
we treat our priorities as the equivalent of that broken water heater,
我们将我们的首要事件视为 那个坏掉的热水器，
by putting them into our schedules first.
将它们优先放入我们的日程表里。
We do this by thinking through our weeks before we are in them.
我们要在事情发生的几周前就先想好。
I find a really good time to do this is Friday afternoons.
我发现周五的下午最适合处理这事儿。
Friday afternoon is what an economist might call
周五的下午是被经济学家称为
a "low opportunity cost" time.
“低机会成本”时间。
Most of us are not sitting there on Friday afternoons saying,
我们大部分人不会在周五下午想着，
"I am excited to make progress
“我要朝我的个人和
toward my personal and professional priorities
职业生涯的首要事件迈进了，
right now."
所以很兴奋。“
(Laughter)
（笑声）
But we are willing to think about what those should be.
但是我们愿意去想那些事是什么。
So take a little bit of time Friday afternoon,
所以在周五下午花一点时间，
make yourself a three-category priority list: career, relationships, self.
为自己做一个分成三类的首要事件的列表： 事业，人际关系，个人。
Making a three-category list reminds us
这样的三项分类列表提醒了我们
that there should be something in all three categories.
每一个类别都应该有一些事。
Career, we think about;
事业，我们经常考虑；
relationships, self --
人际关系，个人——
not so much.
很少会想。
But anyway, just a short list,
无论如何，只要一个短短的列表，
two to three items in each.
每个都包含两到三件事。
Then look out over the whole of the next week,
它们会帮助我们看清下周，
and see where you can plan them in.
如何在下周计划这些事情。
Where you plan them in is up to you.
你可以决定如何计划。
I know this is going to be more complicated for some people than others.
这可能对一些人来说会比较困难一点。
I mean, some people's lives are just harder than others.
我的意思是，有些人的 人生就是比较复杂。
It is not going to be easy to find time to take that poetry class
如果你自己有好几个要照顾的小孩，
if you are caring for multiple children on your own.
想要找时间去参加诗歌班一定不容易。
I get that.
我懂。
And I don't want to minimize anyone's struggle.
我不想轻视任何人的困难。
But I do think that the numbers I am about to tell you are empowering.
当是我觉得我接下来要说的数字 是会改变你的想法的。
There are 168 hours in a week.
我们每周都有168个小时。
Twenty-four times seven is 168 hours.
24乘以7是168个小时。
That is a lot of time.
这是一段很长时间。
If you are working a full-time job, so 40 hours a week,
假如你有一个全职的工作， 一周是40个小时，
sleeping eight hours a night, so 56 hours a week --
每晚睡八个小时， 一周是56个小时，
that leaves 72 hours for other things.
我们有剩下72个小时来做其他事情。
That is a lot of time.
这是一段很长的时间。
You say you're working 50 hours a week,
假如你说你每周工作50个小时，
maybe a main job and a side hustle.
比如一份全职和一份兼职。
Well, that leaves 62 hours for other things.
这样你还是有60小时去做其他的事情。
You say you're working 60 hours.
假如你说你每周工作60个小时，
Well, that leaves 52 hours for other things.
你还是有52个小时去做其他的事情。
You say you're working more than 60 hours.
你说你每周工作超过60个小时，
Well, are you sure?
你确定吗？
(Laughter)
（笑声）
There was once a study comparing people's estimated work weeks
曾经有一个研究对比了 人们估计的工作时间，
with time diaries.
和实际的工作日记。
They found that people claiming 75-plus-hour work weeks
他们发现那些表示 工作超过75小时的人，
were off by about 25 hours.
有25小时的误差。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
You can guess in which direction, right?
你可以猜到这个误差 是多了还是少了吧？
Anyway, in 168 hours a week,
无论如何，在一周的168个小时里，
I think we can find time for what matters to you.
我觉得我们总可以找到时间 做我们想做的事。
If you want to spend more time with your kids,
如果你想花时间陪陪你的孩子，
you want to study more for a test you're taking,
或者准备你即将到来的考试，
you want to exercise for three hours and volunteer for two,
你想锻炼两三个小时或者 做两个小时志愿者，
you can.
你都可以的。
And that's even if you're working way more than full-time hours.
即便你的工作时间远超过法定时间。
So we have plenty of time, which is great,
所以我们有很多时间，这很好。
because guess what?
但是你知道吗？
We don't even need that much time to do amazing things.
我们根本不需要那么多时间 去完成一个大目标。
But when most of us have bits of time, what do we do?
但当我们有一点空闲时间的时候， 我们会做什么？
Pull out the phone, right?
拿出手机，是吧？
Start deleting emails.
开始删除邮件。
Otherwise, we're puttering around the house
或者在家里闲逛，
or watching TV.
看电视。
But small moments can have great power.
但是每个不起眼的时刻都潜力无限。
You can use your bits of time
你可以用零星的时间，
for bits of joy.
来获得零星的快乐。
Maybe it's choosing to read something wonderful on the bus
比如说在去上班的公车上
on the way to work.
读一些精彩的东西。
I know when I had a job that required two bus rides
当我以前的工作需要我 每天早上乘两趟公车
and a subway ride every morning,
和一趟地铁的时候，
I used to go to the library on weekends to get stuff to read.
我周末会去图书馆找东西来读。
It made the whole experience almost, almost, enjoyable.
这几乎，几乎让我的生活更丰富了。
Breaks at work can be used for meditating or praying.
工作间隙的休息时间可以 用来冥想或者祷告。
If family dinner is out because of your crazy work schedule,
如果你因为工作忙 而不能吃家庭晚餐，
maybe family breakfast could be a good substitute.
试一下家庭早餐。
It's about looking at the whole of one's time
这就是看着一个人所有的时间，
and seeing where the good stuff can go.
然后找到什么时候可以做想做的事。
I truly believe this.
我真的相信，
There is time.
我们都有充分的时间。
Even if we are busy,
就算我们很忙，
we have time for what matters.
我们仍然有时间去做重要的事。
And when we focus on what matters,
当我们关注在重要的事上时，
we can build the lives we want
我们可以用所拥有的时间
in the time we've got.
创造我们想要的生活。
Thank you.
谢谢。
(Applause)
（鼓掌）